<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Days_of_Back on Loner Bytes</title>
    <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/categories/days_of_back/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Days_of_Back on Loner Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/categories/days_of_back/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 05</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-05/</guid>
      <description>Cover up the best on this week 1. Coding of the day : None 2. JS of the day : ** Indexed collections and Keyed Collections** Indexed Collections : JavaScript does not have an explicit array data type.
const arr = [45] creates array with one element, Where const arr = Array(45) creates array with no elements but the length of the array.
At the implementation level, JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s arrays actually store their elements as standard object properties, using the array index as the property name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 01</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/communication-w01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/communication-w01/</guid>
      <description>Better than a Yesterday 1. Universal Laws of Communication : Either you having a conversation or you are telling a story or you are issuing a warning or you are not communicating. You are always communicating your creadiabilit, whether you know it or not. All learning involves doing. If your are not in accord with your audiences values, you are not communicating. 2. Golden rule of Communication : Anything thatdistracts people from the message is a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 04</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-04/</guid>
      <description>Becoming Lazy 1. Coding of the day : None 2. JS of the day : Dates/Times and Regular Expressions Dates and Times : JavaScript does not have a date data type. However, you can use the Date object and its methods to work with dates and times in your applications. The Date object has a large number of methods for setting, getting, and manipulating dates. It does not have any properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 03</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-03/</guid>
      <description>Under the pressure 1. Coding of the day : None 2. JS of the day : Expressions / Operations and Numbers / Strings Expressions and Operations : An expression is a valid unit of code that resolves to a value. There are two types of expressions: those that have side effects (such as assigning values) and those that purely evaluate.
Nullish coalescing assignment (??=), also known as the logical nullish assignment operator, only evaluates the right operand and assigns to the left if the left operand is nullish (null or undefined).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 02</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-02/</guid>
      <description>Thought Hard Day 1. Coding of the day : Merge Sort Can&amp;rsquo;t understand the code, but i tried to learn the logic. Merge sort is Divide and Conquer method algorithm. Advantage is in performs well even on large datasets. But it takes large space and it is slower than quick sort because of Not in-place. Not in-place is it requires additional memory to store the sorted data. 2. JS of the day : Loops and Functions Loops and Iterations : Labeled statements are an identifier that lets you refer to it elsewhere in your program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 01</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/day-01/</guid>
      <description>A Starting Journey of 2025 Goals 1. Coding of the day : Selection Sort function selectionSort(array) { int n = array.size(); for(int i = 0; i&amp;lt;n-1;++i) { int minVal = i; for(int j=i+j;j&amp;lt;n;++j) { if(array[j]&amp;lt;array[minVal]) { minVal = j; } } swap(array[i],array[minVal]); } } Advantage of Selection sort is the Memory writes which is better than the Insertion sort and Bubble sort, It makes at most N-1 swaps. Memory Writes is a value overwritten in memory, and Swap operation changes the positions of the elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
