<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>OS on Loner Bytes</title>
    <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/categories/os/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OS on Loner Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/categories/os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learnings of the Day 09/12</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/learning-of-the-day-091223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/learning-of-the-day-091223/</guid>
      <description>Learnings of the Day Today&amp;rsquo;s exploration led to insightful learnings in the realm of operating systems, process lifecycles, creation of processes, termination, and scheduling algorithms.
Process Lifecycle: Importance: Resource Management:
Efficient allocation and deallocation of resources prevent leaks and ensure availability for other processes. Multitasking and Concurrency:
Understanding lifecycles supports concurrent execution and efficient context switching, crucial for multitasking. System Stability and Reliability:
Lifecycle stages ensure isolation, preventing interference between processes and contributing to system stability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings of the Day 08/12</title>
      <link>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/learning-of-the-day-081223/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Cyber-Aju.github.io/Blog/posts/learning-of-the-day-081223/</guid>
      <description>Operating System Concepts Overview Introduction to Operating System (OS): 1. Definition of OS: OS (Operating System): A software that acts as an intermediary between computer hardware and user applications. 2. Why OS? User-Friendly Interface: OS provides a user-friendly interface. Efficient Resource Management: Manages hardware resources efficiently. Security and Virtualization: Ensures security and provides virtualization. 3. Functions of OS: Resource Management: Efficiently allocates and manages hardware resources. Virtualization: Creates a virtual environment for applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
